I swear, milady, I will
not let you down! Huh?
I am resolute and energized!
I am motivated and I am invincible!
System Call!
Generate Thermal Element!
Oh, my God.
It's a strong hope to shine
Come on, let's go
I've hidden voices in the
voice of your voice I've
never been told that you were
Ah, the sound of your voice will be heard
I'll continue to fight with my luck
Back of my soul, ah
I had no idea he could
conjure such spells.
I underestimated him.
That fire giant is a being
made entirely of magic.
My flowers cannot destroy such a thing,
and I doubt they could
hold it off for very long.
How long?
I mean, we don't need that much time,
just enough to get up close to Chudelkin.
For ten seconds. No more.
Perhaps less than that.
Still, you're right.
I'll draw its attention while you attack.
But do not advance too far.
That is what the Pontifex is waiting for.
Ten seconds?
Swarm my flowers!
Go for her eyes. You got it.
System call.
Discharge!
No, no, no, no!
Watch out, you residents!
What's he doing?
No!
Huh?
Ahhh!
Your...
M &M's...
Kirito...
Well, that was rather anticlimactic.
I did gain some useful information from
it, though, so it's not a total loss.
How unsightly.
Heartless creature!
So, irregular boy, I think I've
figured out the mystery of you.
At first, I thought I couldn't see your
properties because you were unregistered.
An illegitimate birth.
But I was wrong.
You're human.
Not from this world.
You're from the other side.
Aren't you?
I am.
So what?
You don't feel threatened by me, do you?
I got the same authority
level as everyone else.
It's nowhere near as high as yours,
that's for sure, Administrator.
Sorry, Queen Nella.
Oh, that little imp.
She's filled your head
with ridiculous stories.
Well, boy, what are you doing in my world?
I doubt you just stumbled
in out of curiosity.
You're right, I didn't.
Your world's gonna end real soon,
and it's gonna be all your fault.
I'm sorry, what?
Are you saying I'll
destroy it? Pretty much.
The Dark Territory will invade.
That's why you made the
Integrity Knights, to stop it.
But your faith in them's your mistake.
They won't be enough.
That sounds exactly like something
that little brat would say.
How pitiful.
Both her for being so desperate to have me
expelled, and you for being so gullible.
Madam Pontifex, if I may.
The army of the Dark has grown rapidly.
If they invade now, the current
number of knights cannot withstand it.
The commander believed so.
As did Vice Commander Fanatio.
And I.
I as well.
What is your plan now that the
Order of Knights is no more?
Do you think you alone
can protect the Empire?
But what angers me more than your hubris?
You have stolen us knights from our
parents, from wives and husbands,
brothers and sisters.
You sealed away our memories
of them and replaced them
with lies of being summoned
from a non-existent heaven.
Pontifex, could you not trust us to be
loyal to you and respect your authority?
Were we such a threat to you?
You had to submit us to such a monstrous
ritual and force our souls into obedience?
I do trust you, though.
In fact, I love you.
The piety module installed in
Unites is proof of my love.
A gift from me to you all.
Why, this little thing frees you from
the worry and pain of normal folk.
You are my beautiful dolls,
beautiful for all eternity.
Out of all the knights, uncle, Commander
Bercouli has shown you the deepest loyalty.
But you do not know the man,
even though he has served you
faithfully for 300 long years.
Do you think he did not
suffer once in all that time?
Did you not know of the pain
he carried in his heart?
Are you that oblivious?
You think so little of me.
Of course I knew.
These things you speak of didn't start
bothering Bercouli recently, though.
He brought them up ages ago.
A century, I think?
Yes, about that, give or take.
I couldn't watch him brood
over such trivialities.
So I fixed him.
Reset him, to be more specific.
And he was not the only one.
I reset every night
more than a century old.
All of their painful memories and
troubling thoughts were wiped away.
Don't you worry, Alice.
I'll overlook your
transgressions and erase
all the thoughts that
make you so miserable,
too.
Before you know it, you'll go back to
being my puppet and have no need to think.
You are correct.
Right now, I feel enough sadness
and pain to tear my heart to pieces.
However, I choose to embrace it.
I do not wish to erase what
I have never felt before.
This pain serves a purpose.
It reminds me what I am.
A human being and not a puppet knight.
Madam Pontifex, I do not want your so-called
love, and I do not need you to fix me!
I'm sad to hear that.
Unfortunately, what you
want doesn't matter.
As soon as I resynthesize you, and I will,
the pesky feelings that trouble
you now will be erased completely.
Kind of like what you did to yourself
way back when, huh, Quinella?
Watch it, little boy.
Dredging up the past is
considered quite rude. Why?
You scared the truth will come out?
No one's got the power to erase the past.
Not even you.
You were born a human and raised a human,
and no matter how much power you got,
that's one thing you
can't change, can you?
I'm not quite sure what you're getting
at, little boy from the outer world.
All you want is to be a god, but you
can never be a god because you're human.
Being human means you make
mistakes, and you made a big one.
At this point, there's
nothing you can do to fix it.
You got less Integrity Knights now.
If the Dark Territory invades,
who's going to stop them?
They'll destroy everything.
And who was the one who corrupted
some of my best knights?
That was you, boy.
If you're all that's left after this, maybe
you can start over with a clean slate.
Maybe that's what you always wanted.
Thing is, it ain't gonna
go the way you want it.
On the other side,
there's the people who created this world
and have final say over
what happens to it.
When they see the human empire fall,
they'll think, Oh well, that didn't work.
I guess we'll start over.
And then, one of them will push a
button and everything will disappear.
The mountains.
The rivers.
The towns.
Every person here and you.
They'll erase it all
in the blink of an eye.
Point taken.
But I have a feeling the
same goes for your world too.
You must have a creator.
Does your kind grapple with the thought of
living under the whim of
a higher power as well?
Do you strive to please this being,
obeying its laws, hoping it won't
tire of you and wipe you out?
I would be shocked if that were the case.
As you say,
your kind created our
world, and if we fail them,
they would delete us without a care.
If that is how your kind treat us, boy,
then you do not have the
right to criticize me.
I reject their authority.
I will not pander to self-proclaimed gods
groveling for the right
to continue existing.
I refute them all.
I exist for one reason alone,
to rule over all in this world.
That singular desire is what
drives me and gives me life.
My legs are for climbing over
others to greater heights,
not to bend at the knee in subjugation!
And then what?
Are you gonna sit back and let
the human empire get destroyed?
Are you gonna watch everything burn?
Alone on your token throne?
a queen with no one to rule?
On the contrary, I will not allow
your kind to reset the underworld,
nor will I allow the final load test?
to run its course either.
I've prepared a new sacred
art to counter that, in fact.
So be honored.
You will be witnesses, the
first to test my creation.
What creation?
The Knights were a stopgap, and
they have served their purpose well.
The military force I require should
not think, or feel, or remember.
In battle, those are distractions.
My perfect soldier relentlessly massacres
whatever enemy stands before it.
Ultimately, what I require is not human.
Wake and destroy your
enemy, my faithful servant,
my soulless exterminator!
Release Recollection!
What's she done? Impossible!
Discharge!
This can't be.
All those weapons?
Using perfect weapon control in
30 at once should be impossible.
Even for the Pontifex.
It violates the sacred arts.
At long last, the power I have sought.
Offensive might with no equal.
A soldier that will fight forever.
Now, what shall I call it?
I know.
The Sword Golem.
No way.
It's a walking sword.
Each one of its blades has the
priority level of a divine object.
I stretched my precious memory
capacity to the limit to create this,
the ultimate weapon.
Do you think you can defeat it?
Now, go forth and fight, my golem!
Go and annihilate your enemies!
Oh.
That's all.
Oh. Oh.
Oh.
Uh…
Ah!
Ah…
Yew-Gio!
Use your dagger!
Stab the levitating disc!
I'll buy you some time.
Hurry!
Oh, my God.
Thank goodness, he made it.
I'm happy I got to fight
with you one last time.
Oh, my God.
Kirito, who is this person?
She's Cardinal.
She's the good pontifex of this world.
Two hundred years ago, she fought
Administrator, but she had to go into hiding.
She saved Eugeo and me and
guided us into the cathedral.
She wants to help.
No one loves this world more than her.
I don't doubt it.
I trust the warmth of her power.
Thank you for healing me, m 'lady.
You stubborn fool.
Did I not relieve you of your duties?
Did I not thank you
for all your hard work?
Why couldn't you just
stay on your bookshelf?
I'm sorry.
Did she have a Fluctlight too?
No.
To borrow a term from your
world, Charlotte was like an NPC.
Wait, what?
But she...
she risked her life to save me.
That's not something an NPC'd do.
I mean, if she didn't have a soul, then...
This child had been alive for 200 years.
She was my constant companion, and she
watched over a number of people for me.
For the past two years, she was with you.
After spending all that time with someone,
one doesn't need a Fluctlight to care.
Even if the nature of an intelligence is
just a collection of input and output data,
it is still possible for it
to have a true soul within.
and in some cases, love.
A concept you'll never
understand as long as you live!
Administrator, you wretched woman!
Thank you so much for watching.
And everything turns to dust to dust
Next time, Administrator.